<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2018-12-14T23:45:39+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alembic</title><subtitle>Alembic is a starting point for Jekyll projects. Rather than starting from scratch, this boilerplate is designed to get the ball rolling immediately</subtitle><author><name>Hector Quintana</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/intro/2018/12/13/Hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2018-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/intro/2018/12/13/Hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/intro/2018/12/13/Hello-world/">&lt;p&gt;“Hello World!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what the first program I ever wrote printed out, actually it just did that and nothing else. Nevertheless, it sparked a curiosity within me that is still going strong to this day. That curiosity has taken me on many paths, allowed me to meet some great people, and caused many late nights. But I wouldn’t change it for anything else. That is why I’ve decided to start this blog, to share my thoughts, experiences, and anything else related to programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not sure what exactly I’ll be posting on here. In the immediate future I’ll be using it as a source of self accountability, logging what I work on each day for personal growth, with tidbits of useful CS tools/sites/knowledge. Please look forward to my next post describing the platfrom this blog is built on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hector Quintana</name></author><summary type="html">“Hello World!” That’s what the first program I ever wrote printed out, actually it just did that and nothing else. Nevertheless, it sparked a curiosity within me that is still going strong to this day. That curiosity has taken me on many paths, allowed me to meet some great people, and caused many late nights. But I wouldn’t change it for anything else. That is why I’ve decided to start this blog, to share my thoughts, experiences, and anything else related to programming. I’m still not sure what exactly I’ll be posting on here. In the immediate future I’ll be using it as a source of self accountability, logging what I work on each day for personal growth, with tidbits of useful CS tools/sites/knowledge. Please look forward to my next post describing the platfrom this blog is built on.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/default-social-image.png" /></entry></feed>