<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-GB"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-GB" /><updated>2018-12-19T07:14:05+00:00</updated><id>https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Alembic</title><subtitle>Alembic is a starting point for Jekyll projects. Rather than starting from scratch, this boilerplate is designed to get the ball rolling immediately</subtitle><author><name>Hector Quintana</name></author><entry><title type="html">Blog Content</title><link href="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/2018/12/19/Blog-Content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Content" /><published>2018-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/2018/12/19/Blog-Content</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/2018/12/19/Blog-Content/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started this blog in part to chronicle my personal growth as a developer, my progress and setbacks. So I’ll be integrating it into my daily routines. The plan at the moment is to write a short blog each morning on what I’ll be studying up on each day. Usually I won’t delve too deeply into these topics, they’ll act maily as a journal and motivator to keep going. So let’s start it off by sharing what’s on my schedule for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;december-19&quot;&gt;December 19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan for today is simple, work on fixing up the blog. I started off the blog with a template and it gets the job done, but it’s not what I want. My resume site has a theme going and the plan is to integrate that site with the blog. So I’ll be updating the colors used throughout, matching the font, and updating the images used. After those tasks are done I’ll rework the home page to be more blog like, do some design to reduce whitespace, and start brainstorming ideas for new in dept blog topics.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hector Quintana</name></author><summary type="html">A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step I started this blog in part to chronicle my personal growth as a developer, my progress and setbacks. So I’ll be integrating it into my daily routines. The plan at the moment is to write a short blog each morning on what I’ll be studying up on each day. Usually I won’t delve too deeply into these topics, they’ll act maily as a journal and motivator to keep going. So let’s start it off by sharing what’s on my schedule for today. December 19 The plan for today is simple, work on fixing up the blog. I started off the blog with a template and it gets the job done, but it’s not what I want. My resume site has a theme going and the plan is to integrate that site with the blog. So I’ll be updating the colors used throughout, matching the font, and updating the images used. After those tasks are done I’ll rework the home page to be more blog like, do some design to reduce whitespace, and start brainstorming ideas for new in dept blog topics.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/assets/default-social-image.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll</title><link href="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/jekyll/2018/12/17/jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll" /><published>2018-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/jekyll/2018/12/17/jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/jekyll/2018/12/17/jekyll/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-and-hyde&quot;&gt;Jekyll and Hyde&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing the blog is currently not in a great state, I’m still learning the ropes of the CMS I’m using. I have experience working with WordPress before, even made a couple of themes for clients. Native HTML with or without frameworks is also no problem for me, it’s actually my preferred method of creating websites. So why go with Jekyll? Let me explain it with three characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speed&quot;&gt;Speed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a web developer working directly with clients one thing you often hear is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Can you make my website faster?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speed is one of the few factors everyone can notice when they load a web page, inherently it’s one of the factors that give a first impression of you. My experience with other CMS such as WordPress is that they are naturally slower than pure HTML, after all they have to connect to a database to get content, plugins, and more. There are ways of speeding pages up, caching comes to mind, but as it is usually a plugin there are issues with it. So Jekyll with it’s native HTML offers me the best speed with no issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;portability&quot;&gt;Portability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Jekyll site can be deployed pretty much anywhere, after building it’s just pure HTML. Other solutions require databases, PHP, or more. They make your site more dynamic but have steeper requirements. As a GitHub Pages user I required a solution that could be run with plain HTML and CSS but was easy to update. Jekyll checked those requirements and even has GitHub integration that moves the build process online, allowing you to even make changes from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;usability&quot;&gt;Usability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is more subjective but I find that Jekyll is much easier to use than other CMS like WordPress. With Jekyll there is no dashboard to log in to, no database, and most importantly no PHP. When adding a new post or making changes I just change the file directly, build, then publish. As a plus Jekyll has the added benifit of not creating more vulnerabilities, no users can login after all. As a CMS Jekyll makes me feel in total control of my site, as I control exactly was is output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly it’s not all great with Jekyll. As the site grows I can see handling large amounts of posts more of a hassle. Other CMS make it easy to modify the site on the go thanks to online dashboards. Jekyll has ways of allowing that but at the moment they’re not working for me. The learning curve for Jekyll was defintely greater than any other CMS I have experience with. With something like WordPress you can be up and running in a couple of minutes but Jekyll defintely took me longer than that to set up. All in all Jekyll is not as plug and play as others but it does leave you with a sense of accomplishment once it’s set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can conclude that while Jekyll is a fine CMS it defenitively is not for everyone. Others provide compeling benifits to offset their cons. But I chose Jekyll because it’s features are what I need at the moment. A light portable blogging tool that allows me to share my thoughts online, all the while letting me take the wheel and decide where I take it. A tool that allows me to get to core of it and do just about anything I can think of. That is why I went down the path of computer science and it’s why I went with Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hector Quintana</name></author><summary type="html">Jekyll and Hyde At the time of writing the blog is currently not in a great state, I’m still learning the ropes of the CMS I’m using. I have experience working with WordPress before, even made a couple of themes for clients. Native HTML with or without frameworks is also no problem for me, it’s actually my preferred method of creating websites. So why go with Jekyll? Let me explain it with three characteristics. Speed As a web developer working directly with clients one thing you often hear is: Can you make my website faster? Speed is one of the few factors everyone can notice when they load a web page, inherently it’s one of the factors that give a first impression of you. My experience with other CMS such as WordPress is that they are naturally slower than pure HTML, after all they have to connect to a database to get content, plugins, and more. There are ways of speeding pages up, caching comes to mind, but as it is usually a plugin there are issues with it. So Jekyll with it’s native HTML offers me the best speed with no issues. Portability A Jekyll site can be deployed pretty much anywhere, after building it’s just pure HTML. Other solutions require databases, PHP, or more. They make your site more dynamic but have steeper requirements. As a GitHub Pages user I required a solution that could be run with plain HTML and CSS but was easy to update. Jekyll checked those requirements and even has GitHub integration that moves the build process online, allowing you to even make changes from your phone. Usability This one is more subjective but I find that Jekyll is much easier to use than other CMS like WordPress. With Jekyll there is no dashboard to log in to, no database, and most importantly no PHP. When adding a new post or making changes I just change the file directly, build, then publish. As a plus Jekyll has the added benifit of not creating more vulnerabilities, no users can login after all. As a CMS Jekyll makes me feel in total control of my site, as I control exactly was is output. Admittedly it’s not all great with Jekyll. As the site grows I can see handling large amounts of posts more of a hassle. Other CMS make it easy to modify the site on the go thanks to online dashboards. Jekyll has ways of allowing that but at the moment they’re not working for me. The learning curve for Jekyll was defintely greater than any other CMS I have experience with. With something like WordPress you can be up and running in a couple of minutes but Jekyll defintely took me longer than that to set up. All in all Jekyll is not as plug and play as others but it does leave you with a sense of accomplishment once it’s set up. Closing Thoughts We can conclude that while Jekyll is a fine CMS it defenitively is not for everyone. Others provide compeling benifits to offset their cons. But I chose Jekyll because it’s features are what I need at the moment. A light portable blogging tool that allows me to share my thoughts online, all the while letting me take the wheel and decide where I take it. A tool that allows me to get to core of it and do just about anything I can think of. That is why I went down the path of computer science and it’s why I went with Jekyll.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/assets/default-social-image.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/intro/2018/12/13/Hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2018-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/intro/2018/12/13/Hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/general/intro/2018/12/13/Hello-world/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hello World!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s what the first program I ever wrote printed out, actually it just did that and nothing else. Nevertheless, it sparked a curiosity within me that is still going strong to this day. That curiosity has taken me on many paths, allowed me to meet some great people, and caused many late nights. But I wouldn’t change it for anything else. That is why I’ve decided to start this blog, to share my thoughts, experiences, and anything else related to programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not sure what exactly I’ll be posting on here. In the immediate future I’ll be using it as a source of self accountability, logging what I work on each day for personal growth, with tidbits of useful CS tools/sites/knowledge. Please look forward to my next post describing the platfrom this blog is built on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Hector Quintana</name></author><summary type="html">“Hello World!” That’s what the first program I ever wrote printed out, actually it just did that and nothing else. Nevertheless, it sparked a curiosity within me that is still going strong to this day. That curiosity has taken me on many paths, allowed me to meet some great people, and caused many late nights. But I wouldn’t change it for anything else. That is why I’ve decided to start this blog, to share my thoughts, experiences, and anything else related to programming. I’m still not sure what exactly I’ll be posting on here. In the immediate future I’ll be using it as a source of self accountability, logging what I work on each day for personal growth, with tidbits of useful CS tools/sites/knowledge. Please look forward to my next post describing the platfrom this blog is built on.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://alembic.darn.es/hpquintana.github.io/blog/assets/default-social-image.png" /></entry></feed>